Snejkumar Jayantilal Hirpara

Junagadh, Gujarat → +91 9726339294 ✓ snejhirpara123@gmail.com ÇGitHub in LinkedIn

CAREER PROFILE

As a computer science student and an enthusiast about web and android development with experience in building simple websites and mobile apps, excited to apply my knowledge and gain hands-on experience through working with the industry.

EDUCATION

U. V. Patel College of Engineering, Mehsana	10/2020 - $present$
B. Tech in Information Technology	CGPA - 8.22/10
Alpha Vidhya Sankul, Junagadh HSC(GSEB)	06/2018-05/2020 55.54%
Eklavya Public School, Junagadh	06/2017-06/2018
SSC(GSEB)	71.16%

EXPERIENCE

Intern at TechnoHacks EduTech - Web Developer Intern

Remote - 07/2023-Present

• Designed Web Applications with attractive UI and improved responsiveness using ReactJS and Tailwind CSS Framework. Used APIs in the website using NodeJS and ExpressJS frameworks.

Front-End (XML) Designer in Android - Student Attendance Application

01/2023-05/2023

- Designs of some screens of the attendance app
- QR Code Generation by entering the text as input

PROJECTS

Student Leave & Attendance Management System | Android, XML, Kotlin

- It's an Android application that captures a real-time image and marks attendance. And through this app, the student can apply for leave also.
- Task: Designed UI for this project to provide a better view of the application to the students.

NewsMonkey Web Application | ReactJS, NodeJS, and News API | GitHub

• Developed NewsMonkey web application that uses News API and provides dynamically updated news to the user. The BootStrap CSS Framework is used for responsive design.

TextUtils Web App | ReactJS, BootStrap | GitHub | Live

 Developed a TextUtils Web Application which provides basic text utilities like converting text to upper and lower case, removing extra spaces, word count, minutes to read the paragraph, etc.

CurrencyConverter Web App | ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Currency Converter API | GitHub

 Developed a Currency Converter Web Application which has good UI and it uses Currency Converter API to convert the amount into around 170 different country's currencies.

SKILLS

Languages/Frameworks: C/C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, XML (For Android UI)

Developer Tools: VS Code, Android Studio

Technology: ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, Android

Other: Communication Skills, Teamwork, Problem-Solving, Microsoft Word & PowerPoint

ACHIEVEMENTS & CERTIFICATES

- Winner in Android CampusFest 2023 (01/2023-01/2023)
- Certificate of Appreciation in Android Campus Fest by Android Educators (01/2023)
- Certificate of Communication Skills by TCS (06/2023)
- Certificate of TCS iON Career Edge Young Professional (06/2023)
- JavaScript By Sololearn (05/2021)